KEN EUCKER

@ keneucker@gmail.com

a Portland, OR 97218

keneucker.com

linkedin.com/in/keneucker

github.com/keneucker

SKILLS

- HTML
- Javascript
- CSS
- NodeJs
- PHP
- Mysql
- AWS services (EC2, Lambda, S3, Cloudfront)
- Google Cloud Platform and Comp ute Engine
- C#
- MSSQL
- ASP. NET

EDUCATION

Oregon Institute of Technology Jun 2010

Bachelor's of Science: Computer So ftware Engineering Technology

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Hello, world! I love to design applications, write poetry, ride my bicycle, hike to hot springs, backpack through forests, take candid photographs, and talk about the intersection of technology and psychology.

I am a full stack web developer, classically trained in object oriented programming, who likes to write universal javascript, with extensive experience building the backend of web connected properties. I have a diverse set of skills writing in the serverside languages C#, , PHP Javascript, and the clientside languages HTML, Javascript, CSS, JSX, including the database languages mysql, MSSQL, and Mongodb. I seek to help others with their relationship with technology through software solutions both web and native.

WORK HISTORY

Digital Trends - Web Developer Portland, Oregon • 03/2017 - 12/2018

- Full Stack Web Developer working in PHP Node, HTML, and Javascript on a Wordpress platform that serves content to over 5,000 concurrent users a day.
- Daily participant in standup meetings, software project planning meetings, and system architecture meetings.
- During my time at Digital Trends I developed a new ESP integration from the ground up using test-driven development methodologies, refactored newsletter emails and the code that runs the signup modules on the site, implemented a couple of linking features on our articles, and implemented a new article type with a slideshow; all for the WordPress platform of digitaltrends.com.
- My greatest work at Digital Trends is an end to end solution for encapsulating our adcode with site-specific integration code and business logic which is deployed to AWS S3, Lambda, and Api Gateway. A project that started as a skunkworks solution for my own process which I whole heartedly developed into a fully featured build automation tool.
- · I also upped my foosball game.

Seven Twenty Studios LLC - Software Engineer Portland, Oregon • 06/2011 - 01/2017

- I managed a Single Member LLC as a freelancing business and traveled while working remote contracts.
- Custom software development and systems architecture engineer for web connected technologies in both the business and personal sectors.
- I worked on small teams as a collaborative developer as well as consulting with interactive producers to provide long term architectural designs that benefit the business needs that clients are looking for.

SOLID Interactive - Web Developer Portland, Oregon • 03/2016 - 12/2016

- At Solid; I was involved in client meetings, standups, development planning sessions, and company wide tactic meetings as a web developer.
- Interfaced with project managers and clients to provide new features and implementations to existing sites as well as maintenance and issues that arise.
- Participated with other developers on the team in sprint planning, story and defect weighting, and tech roundtables about new and exciting technologies.

R/West - Web Developer
Portland, Oregon • 03/2014 - 04/2015

• Backend web services developer and software architecture designer focusing on projects in php, mysql, javascript, and html. I developed version 1 into version 2 of a platform that saw growth and scale.

Viewpoint Construction Software - Software Development Engineer Portland, Oregon • 12/2011 - 01/2014

- Developer role in scrum process on systems team: attended daily scrums, participated in weighting sprints, defect ticket management.
- Coordinated development efforts with Project Manager, Support, and Quality Assurance teams.
- Core development in ASP.NET C#, Multi-Tier SQL, VB.NET Winforms on flagship Viewpoint Construction Software.

Overland Agency - Software Developer 1 Portland, Oregon • 05/2010 - 07/2011

- Worked mostly in bug fixing, qa testing, and feature improvement of a proprietary CMS offering customizations for various clients which was built in ASP.NET using MySql.
- Lead Silverlight development for all projects: "Fresh Local Music"

 Delivered a Silverlight out of browser music app that runs on laptops in the store locations and updates external database.